Personal information

Name / Surname
Telephone
Personal Email
Date of birth
Github profile
Website

Paolo Scaramuzza

+39 3461724250 paoscr@gmail.com 16 December, 1992

https://github.com/electricant https://paolo.scaramuzza.me



About

I thrive on the challenges inherent in the electronic engineering landscape. With a solid foundation in both theoretical principles and practical applications, I am equipped to tackle complex engineering challenges with confidence and precision. My portfolio showcases numerous electronic projects. With a keen eye for detail and a drive for excellence, I specialize in bringing concepts to life with precision and creativity.

Working Experience

Oct. 2019 - present

Hardware RF application engineer at **u-blox Italia S.p.A.**

In my role, I undertake the design and release of demo boards for cellular modules, along with composing detailed documentation. Additionally, I provide support to customers in refining and validating their designs, while also maintaining technical communication with business partners.

Oct. 2017 - May 2018

Internship at Infineon Technologies Villach, Austria

The internship was focused on the design and measurement of integrated 28 GHz power amplifiers for 5G cellular networks.

Skills

Electronics

Analog, RF and Digital Electronics Design

CAD Tools

Altium, Cadence Allegro, Cadence Virtuoso, ADS, KiCAD, LTSPICE. Electromagnetic simulations with HFSS, ADS Momentum and Sonnet.

Prototyping & Testing

 $\label{eq:analog_RF_mixed-signal} Analog/RF/mixed-signal circuits measurement and characterization. Radiated \& conducted RF characterization of cellular devices according to ETSI/3GPP/FCC standards.$

Programming languages

C, C++, Perl, Python, MATLAB, lisp and other functional programming languages. Web programming knowledge.

Project Management

Ensure the seamless execution of electronic engineering initiatives, from planning to delivery, while optimizing resources and mitigating risks.

Version Control Systems

Familiarity with version control tools like Git, SVN & Perforce for managing project files and collaborating with team members.

Communication Skills

Effective communication skills for conveying technical concepts to stakeholders, team members, and collaborators.

Self-assessment European level^(*)

English German Slovene

Understanding		Speaking		Writing
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1 Proficient user				
A2 Basic user				
A1 Basic user				

^(*) Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

March 2011

Certificate in Advanced English (CAE)

Other Activities

Electronics Engineering Consultant

Leveraging my extensive expertise to provide tailored solutions and strategic guidance to clients navigating complex electronic design challenges.

Education

Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2019

Ph.D. in Information Engineering, University of Padova

Topic: Fully-integrated Power Amplifiers for 5G Communications

(supervisor: Andrea Neviani, Andrea Bevilacqua)

Nov. 2018

During the Ph.D., was awarded at the **Huawei Italy University Challenge** in Pavia, aimed at inspiring research in Silicon Integrated Circuits for Analog, RF, mmWave and Optical transceivers

July 2017

Qualification test (esame di stato) for being a professional Engineer

2014 - 2016

Master's degree in Electronics Engineering (110/110 cum laude)

University of Padova, thesis title: "Project of a Class J Power Amplifier in Integrated Bipolar Technology"

June 2015

While studying for his M.Sc, received the Roberto Rocca Education Program scolarship for academic merit.

2011 - 2014

Bachelor's degree in Information Engineering (110/110)

University of Padova, thesis title: "A Study on the Efficiency of Integrated LC Oscillators for Ultra Wideband Impulse Radio Transmission"

2006 - 2011

Liceo Scientifico "Duca degli Abruzzi" in Gorizia

Publications

TCAS-I 2018

P. Scaramuzza, C. Rubino, M. Caruso, M. Tiebout, A. Bevilacqua, and A. Neviani

 ${\it Class-J~SiGe~X-Band~Power~Amplifier~Using~a~Ladder~Filter-Based~AM-PM~Distortion~Reduction~Technique}$

ESSCIRC 2017

P. Scaramuzza, C. Rubino, M. Tiebout, M. Caruso, M. Ortner,

A. Neviani, and A. Bevilacqua

Class-AB and Class-J 22dBm SiGe HBT PAs for X-Band Radar Systems